Roy Justus Papers
Roy Justus Papers
- Artwork
  - By Justus
    - 1966 Jul-Dec, 115 items (Oversize 39)
      Oct 10: I can really sympathize with LBJ (GOP elephant and GOP consensus)
      Oct 11: Hello, there (Russian bear waving to U.S. eagle, seated between snorting Chinese dragon)
      Oct 12: Hallucinations (inflation and food prices)
      Oct 13: Still freedom's bulwark (the free press)
      Oct 14: Sooner or later (satchel ticking - Minn. sales tax)
      Oct 17: What a sanctuary (dove of peace in war-torn forest of wild-life refuge)
      Oct 20: The mountain is about to come to Mohammed (junked trucks, trains, and planes)
      Oct 21: But where are the issues? (charges and counter-charges in Minnesota elections)
      Oct 24: When do we get to the roots? (man chopping at tree of civil rights violence with roots of the negro ghettos)
      Oct 25: Have mercy (the world entreating the stork of population explosion)
      Oct 26: Still the best hope for peace (United Nations flying flag of world law)
      Oct 26: Most promising young man of his class (tattered man sitting on suitcase the great society)
      Oct 27: About this time in the campaign (tired voter and the elections)
      Oct 31: Recognize me? (Mao with the A bomb)
      Nov 1: On the home front (the voter being pulled by GOP elephant and democratic donkey)
      Nov 2: No place to hide (the world running from nuclear proliferation)
      Nov 3: The "ax" in "tax"
      Nov 4: (no caption) (bombs crushing world disarmament)
      Nov 7: On stage
      Nov 8: Experience is not always the best teacher (the world about to blow out his brains with revolver of the atom)
      Nov 9: Congratulations (tattered and ragged donkey and elephant shaking hands after elections)
      Nov 10: There ain't no such bird (LBJ and flying elephant of GOP consensus)
      Nov 11: Why, that's old Mr. GOP, isn't it? (happy, singing GOP elephant striding along beside house for all to see)
      Nov 14: No, I am not a defeated candidate - I'm a defeated analyst
      Nov 15: The big parade (missile, anti-missile, ad infinitum)
      Nov 16: I must have been carried away
      Nov 17: Looks more like a hummingbird to me (stork of population explosion)
      Nov 18: Grim score keeper (death marking war's casualty list - our side and their side)
      Nov 21: Pollution in Europe, too (Nazi-ism waters pouring out of pipe)
      Nov 22: Someone's knocking at his door (opportunity with needs of the 20th century at door of GOP)
      Nov 23: Not one of our best astronauts (Old bearded man of U.S. China policy astride snail at night)
      Nov 24: He ought to bring. Hoe so7ething
      Nov 25: Whatever happened to the one-world concept?
      Nov 28: Detour (LBJ driving car of great society down road of cutback in highway aids)
      Nov 29: New resolve (GOP elephant skipping rope - the 1968 presidency)
      Nov 30: Major rendezvous failure
      Dec 1: What of the harvest?
      Dec 2: Do your Christmas shopping early
      Dec 5: Still haunting (GOP elephant shivering in bed at the ghost of the Goldwater campaign split)
      Dec 6: Looking him straight in the eye (cowboy LBJ staring at bull - the budget)
      Dec 7: Powder keg (Black Power - South Africa, Rhodesia)
      Dec 8: Basic war on poverty problem (tattered world bowed down by arms cost bombs)
      Dec 9: More recent photo of the moon (nuclear arms banned in outer space, et cetera)
      Dec 12: Revised (GOP elephant carrying el GOP is not dead)
      Dec 13: Merry Christmas
      Dec 13: Merry Christmas (cartoon has been sent on loan to postmaster general, Washington, DC, for an exhibition; not included in present inventory)
      Dec 14: Santa's dilemma (Santa LBJ putting a bomb in hung stocking of anti-poverty)
      Dec 15: What's a school for, anyway?
      Dec 19: Wary snake charmer (GOP enticing one out of consensus basket)
      Dec 20: Truces
      Dec 21: What did you expect - roses? (nuclear weapons sprouting anti-missiles)
      Dec 22: By cracky - a mandate
      Dec 23: Persevering fellow
      Dec 26: Fancy meeting you here (U.S. And Russia carrying sacks of their wheat to India)
      Dec 27: Beatnik (right wing GOP elephant carrying sign the great society is dead)
      Dec 28: Will LBJ run in '68? (GOP elephant and LBJ gazing at crystal ball)
      Dec 29: The uneven contest (war tanks rushing over dove of peace)
    - 1967 Jan-Jun, 121 items (Oversize 40)
      Jan 2: The bequest
      Jan 3: At last - a consensus
      Jan 4: The dialogue
      Jan 5: Now don't expect too much - after all I'm only human!
      Jan 6: Hey, pop, what do they an by 'credibility gap'?
      Jan 10: Still in the bronco stage
      Jan 11: Snowmen
      Jan 12: Have patience!
      Jan 13: Let them eat bombs!
      Jan 16: What've you got in your hand?
      Jan 17: The united states is bigger than Texas, after all!
      Jan 18: Where the action is!
      Jan 19: Imbalance of nature
      Jan 20: Wow - that's good!
      Jan 23: Bang!
      Jan 24: What a wonderful bird is the pelican!
      Jan 25: A five to four decision!
      Jan 26: The chronic case
      Jan 27: You've got the ball - run with it!!
      Jan 30: Get going! - you're holding up my department!
      Jan 31: Co-existence or co-extinction?
      Feb 1: Wrecking ball
      Feb 2: Things are going to be nice an' green in the spring!
      Feb 3: Grand Canyon of communism
      Feb 6: One of these days I should do something about this!
      Feb 7: Could one of them be a live one?
      Feb 8: And now in the zoo!
      Feb 9: Just the first act you know!
      Feb 10: Like I say - the only good lobby bill is a dead lobby bill!
      Feb 13: Escalation with a bang!
      Feb 14: The veteran
      Feb 15: Isn't intelligence involved in education?
      Feb 16: Fouling his nest
      Feb 17: Self-appointed traffic cop
      Feb 20: Che7's special
      Feb 21: - for forty days and forty nights!
      Feb 28: Daddy!
      Mar 2: Mao's thoughts!
      Mar 3: Homework
      Mar 6: Not the worst thing I ever saw (Lyndon Johnson, Great Society)
      Mar 8: Ebb and flow
      Mar 9: Any aberrations or anything?
      Mar 10: Where do you think you're going?
      Mar 13: Off the wagon again!
      Mar 14: An old slogan up-to-date
      Mar 15: To be, or not to be - that is the question!
      Mar 16: Lecture series on ethics
      Mar 17: Knock, knock - who's there?
      Mar 20: Well, well
      Mar 21: Bonanza!
      Mar 22: Still looking for a landing strip
      Mar 23: Deciding a delinquency case!
      Mar 24: There must be an alternative!
      Mar 27: The ugliest thing I ever saw!
      Mar 28: Handicap race
      Mar 29: - and never the twain shall meet!
      Mar 30: The war on poverty!
      Mar 31: Peck's bad boy
      Apr 3: Five years of progress!
      Apr 4: At least you can give me a consensus (Lyndon Johnson, Democrats)
      Apr 5: Chinese puzzle craze!
      Apr 6: The old soldier
      Apr 7: 'Twixt spinach and strawberry shortcake
      Apr 10: Not a very good incubator!
      Apr 11: Where do I start - top or bottom?
      Apr 12: If these birth control nuts had their way where would I get my armies?
      Apr 13: The war is not an issue!.
      Apr 14: The man who came to dinner
      Apr 17: Now to translate that into action!
      Apr 18: Every week is national library week!
      Apr 19: Go home!
      Apr 20: The old lady who lived in a shot',. -
      Apr 21: The age of extremism
      Apr 24: Those good old styles are returning!
      Apr 25: Trying to keep a cork under water
      Apr 26: It could have been a lot worse!
      Apr 27: Babes in the woods
      Apr 28: Hot ones
      May 1: Hardy perennial
      May 2: About to try it again
      May 3: Sooner or later
      May 4: Sometimes I think this might become an issue!
      May 5: Confrontation!
      May 8: Something new has been added
      May 9: We can't really blame him, can we?
      May 10: Still beating the stuffing out of it!
      May 11: Insomnia
      May 12: Stupid! - can't you see I'm saving you from communism?
      May 15: Can't you read?
      May 16: Tough going, up or down
      May 16: Tough going - up or down!
      May 17: Jerry-built?
      May 18: If it ain't one damned thing it's another!
      May 19: His own handiwork
      May 22: Yeah - I can hear the trumpet, but what does it mean?
      May 23: There's another one!
      May 24: Some of my best friends are dictators
      May 24: Some of my best friends are dictators!
      May 25: Prospects, prospects, prospects
      May 26: Who will be the candidates in '68?
      May 29: Sort op a beatnik approach!
      May 30: The roots are deep
      May 31: Don't you understand? - you're under arrest!
      Jun 1: Whir a crazy place!
      Jun 2: We do have com1mitments, you know!
      Jun 5: A stranger in these parts
      Jun 6: But, lady, this is my life
      Jun 7: Now, who will save the maiden?
      Jun 8: Damit - say something!
      Jun 9: Bullets will never stop him!
      Jun 12: Strange what a burden a piece of paper can be!
      Jun 13: The reluctant cop
      Jun 14: The good-bad guy is still wrestling with himself!
      Jun 15: The old gusher
      Jun 16: The interlude
      Jun 19: The lady and the dragon
      Jun 20: A good observation tower
      Jun 21: Shouting is better than shooting
      Jun 22: The substitute for disarmament
      Jun 23: It fluctuates!
      Jun 26: While he is at it he'd better dig one for himself, too!
    - 1967 Jul-Dec, 116 items (Oversize 41)
      Jul 4: Will the mountain come to Mahomet?
      Jul 5: Trying to decode the smoke signals!
      Jul 6: Spoiling his siesta
      Jul 7: Free-election campaigning in Vietnam
      Jul 10: The laboratory experiment
      Jul 11: A name-something like Solomon
      Jul 12: Aren't you interested in defending yourself against communism?
      Jul 13: The great nuclear arms race!
      Jul 14: And no social security!
      Jul 17: Hazards at home, too (Lyndon Johnson, isolationism)
      Jul 18: Not the torch of liberty
      Jul 19: Plight of the rescuer!
      Jul 20: These infernal sonic booms!
      Jul 21: So far they're just little brush fires!
      Jul 24: The old California wagon
      Jul 25: The tinderbox
      Jul 28: Boomerang?
      Jul 31: The belated conformist
      Aug 1: At the bottom of the riot rubble
      Aug 2: Post-riot riot
      Aug 3: Of all the indignities!
      Aug 4: Don't look now, but -
      Aug 7: Let's pull for the shore (inflation, Lyndon Johnson, Congress)
      Aug 8: Rather old stuff, after all!
      Aug 9: Voice from the state department
      Aug 10: Dear diary...
      Aug 10: Dear diary!
      Aug 11: Not enough in this troubled world!
      Aug 14: Free election?
      Aug 15: And if this is not a paper dragon?
      Aug 16: Pennant rash is almost never fatal!
      Aug 17: Road to the castle
      Aug 19: Sometimes I think Asia might be bigger 'n Texas!
      Aug 21: Global vendor
      Aug 24: Anything new on Vietnam?
      Aug 29: Anything new on Vietnam?
      Aug 30: You're running the wrong way! - you're running the wrong way!!!
      Aug 31: D0'1ino theory in practice!
      Sep 1: Twins on a seesaw
      Sep 4: Government sometimes wonders if you, too, have a credibility gap!
      Sep 5: What will come out of it?
      Sep 6: Kind of a mixed market!
      Sep 7: I.Q. test
      Sep 8: Rough on the animals, too!
      Sep 11: The young conservatives
      Sep 12: Burr under the saddle!
      Sep 13: Apparently planet earth. Is having a civil nap!
      Sep 14: A basic principle of democracy
      Sep 15: A good beginning!
      Sep 18: Target practice?
      Sep 19: Treading on eggs!
      Sep 20: Brainwashing is old stuff!
      Sep 21: Mao will understand we're not trying for a bull's eye!
      Sep 22: What I really want is a consensus!
      Sep 25: How about bouncing the bouncer?
      Sep 26: Now get going on those anti-anti-missile missiles!
      Sep 27: Escalation here too
      Sep 27: Escalation here too!
      Sep 28: My, how you have grown
      Sep 29: The assault
      Oct 2: The right of dissent
      Oct 3: The great '63 political race!
      Oct 4: Puritanism-1967
      Oct 5: Vietnam casualties
      Oct 6: New thriller - and it isn't fiction
      Oct 9: The ultimate escalation
      Oct 10: It's a lot harder to fix the roof after it starts raining
      Oct 11: The nightmare
      Oct 12: How considerate of them - wonder how they're doing on their own planet!
      Oct 13: Judeo-Christian bargain days in Minnesota
      Oct 16: You're getting warmer (Lyndon Johnson, escalation, World War III
      Oct 17: The third force
      Oct 18: How about another little drink?
      Oct 19: Forward pass!
      Oct 20: The old oaken bucket (consensue); signed and inscribed to Elizabeth Wells
      Oct 23: A job for king Solomon
      Oct 24: Good time for him to go fishing
      Oct 25: Considering everything, my convalescence is quite remarkable!
      Oct 26: The atomic neurotic!
      Oct 27: The persistent camel
      Oct 30: I can't hear you!
      Oct 31: High voltage
      Nov 1: I don't get it!
      Nov 2: Ps-s-st!
      Nov 6: These are nervous times
      Nov 7: The snowball
      Nov 8: Those grapes may not be too sour, after all!
      Nov 9: The citizen who kept his cool!
      Nov 10: Not very well-heeled!
      Nov 13: Fanatic poker game
      Nov 14: Pacification on the home front, too (Lyndon Johnson, dissenting Democrats)
      Nov 15: Another poverty area
      Nov 16: Winning the hearts and minds of the Orientals?
      Nov 17: Better get going, mister!
      Nov 20: Just in the nick of time!
      Nov 21: Vietnam census taker
      Nov 22: Leashed
      Nov 22: Leashed!
      Nov 23: High cost of killing
      Nov 24: Not even a mirage!
      Nov 27: - to beautify the freeways!
      Nov 28: The golden calf
      Nov 29: I can lick anybody in the house!
      Nov 30: No caption
      Dec 1: He huffs and he puffs
      Dec 4: The dissenter
      Dec 6: You too?
      Dec 6: You, too!?
      Dec 7: Great metropolitan center!
      Dec 8: Who'll volunteer to hold down this pressure?
      Dec 11: No caption
      Dec 12: Thin-ice season!
      Dec 13: But, first, define your ideologies!
      Dec 14: Does this make sense?
      Dec 15: Living by the sword!
      Dec 18: Irresistible force and immovable object?
    - 1968 Jan-Jun (Oversize 44)
      Jan 3: Buck up! You've got a big job ahead of you!
      Jan 4: The thinker
      Jan 9: Now what do I do with it?!
      Jan 10: Go ahead and talk!
      Jan 11: The growth of isolationism in this country must be stopped!
      Jan 12: Casting its shadow
      Jan 15: We're getting some action now!
      Jan 18: Another poll
      Jan 19: Leftovers - but good!?
      Jan 22: Moonlighting
      Jan 24: Don't be alarmed - it's foolproof!
      Jan 25: Horrors! It's spreading!
      Jan 25: Horrors - it's spreading!
      Jan 26: I can bring peace to the world!
      Jan 29: Great invention in the atomic age!
      Jan 30: Leaving no doubt of a need for the commission!
      Jan 31: Fiddling!
      Feb 2: Here we go again!
      Feb 5: Vietnam casualty
      Feb 7: No caption
      Feb 8: Civilization marches on!
      Feb 9: Flower children
      Feb 12: My Vietnam coonskin!
      Feb 13: I'd like to get my finger on that there button!
      Feb 14: I don't want to be critical but we do need more effort on your part!
      Feb 19: Population explosion-garbage explosion
      Feb 20: Why don't you go away?
      Feb 21: Ever think of ditching the whole bloomin' business?
      Feb 23: Buck up - throw your shoulders back and smile!
      Feb 23: Buck up - throw your shoulders back - and smile!
      Feb 26: He couldn't care less!
      Feb 27: Are you nuts? - there. Ain't no down escalator!
      Feb 28: Which is the more civilized riot-control weapon?
      Feb 29: Just right to sweep things under!
      Mar 4: Se-e-e-e-x!
      Mar 5: The finger!
      Mar 11: And how about a 'jab or war?
      Mar 12: I've got a secret!
      Mar 13: The greater the escalation-the greater the victory!
      Mar 14: Funniest thing I ever saw!
      Mar 15: Hey Mac! Where did you get those nice juicy apples?
      Mar 15: Hey, Mac! - where did you get those nice juicy apples?!
      Mar 18: World cop
      Mar 19: Sometimes called Chicago!
      Mar 20: No caption
      Mar 22: What's wrong with it?
      Mar 25: I'm tired!
      Mar 28: I think this guy is really serious about all this moral values stuff!
      Mar 29: Whatsa matter - doncha love me?
      Apr 1: I shot an arrow into the air
      Apr 2: The situation is fluid
      Apr 2: The situation is fluid!
      Apr 3: Gee, uncle - you're not planning to leave me all alone, are you?!
      Apr 4: Owe on - give it another try!
      Apr 5: Ferdinand
      Apr 6: My son, my son -
      Apr 8: Black man's burden
      Apr 9: Time for reflection
      Apr 10: I'm about to send you on a most difficult mission
      Apr 10: I'm about to send you on a most difficult mission -
      Apr 11: Action too often requires tragedy
      Apr 12: Pop - I want a gun!
      Apr 16: Peace feelers
      Apr 17: - and they both want to ride him
      Apr 18: Another fellow with gun trouble
      Apr 19: I'm not going anyplace, any time!
      Apr 22: Where is the dough, Mr. president?
      Apr 22: Where is the dove, Mr. President?
      Apr 23: Peace poker game
      Apr 24: Textbooks
      Apr 25: Big, isn't it?
      Apr 26: Humphrey, McCarthy, Kennedy, Nixon, Rockefeller, Wallace...?
      Apr 30: No caption
      May 2: But we must move into the 20th century!
      May 7: Caught in a badminton game
      May 8: You big bullies!
      May 9: Now you must have patience!
      May 10: I may have to destroy you to save you!
      May 13: A little louder, please!
      May 15: Peace ballet
      May 16: Where have we gone wrong?
      May 17: Go fishing: get away from it all
      May 20: The mountain comes to Mahomet:
      May 23: Revolution on the campus
      May 24: I've won - why don't you quit?
      May 27: Beware of falling rocks!
      May 28: Beautiful!
      May 29: Scrambled eggs coming up!
      May 30: No caption
      May 31: The echo
      Jun 3: Still tilting with windmills!
      Jun 4: Now for a little peace and quiet!
      Jun 5: Most stubborn domino I ever saw!
      Jun 6: Nightmare
      Jun 7: No caption
      Jun 10: It'll take a lot of repairing!
      Jun 11: The cold line
      Jun 12: Fall-out
      Jun 13: I just use it for target practice!
      Jun 14: Say a-h-h-h!
      Jun 17: Speaking of gun control!
      Jun 18: The case of the stolen elephant!
      Jun 19: A hundred years old and better than a new one!
      Jun 20: Gosh, what a wonderful gadget!
      Jun 21: Ever hear of the 'new politics'? 1972
      Jun 24: The old shell game
      Jun 26: Guns, guns, guns
      Jun 27: Looking for a consensus!
      Jun 28: It says USA and USSR are talking about gun controls!
    - 1968 Jul-Dec (Oversize 45)
      Jul 1: Big man on campus
      Jul 2: Then it's agreed we have enough!
      Jul 3: Democracy is still functioning!
      Jul 4: I'm not a racist - I'm a big tipper!
      Jul 5: Free agent
      Jul 8: Hardly the great American debate
      Jul 9: You're out o' style, fella!
      Jul 10: She can always expect to be stoned!
      Jul 11: One thing the polls make clear!
      Jul 12: No caption
      Jul 15: Commenting on issues of the day
      Jul 30: I said: what is this younger generation coming to?!
      Jul 31: He who would play Atlas
      Aug 1: I guess we'll have to fall back on you old experts
      Aug 5: Miami extravaganza
      Aug 6: Darned crossroads again!
      Aug 7: The platform
      Aug 8: Making like a dove
      Aug 9: I would rather be 'right' than be president!
      Aug 12: I always say - one success deserves another
      Aug 13: Difficult days for dogmatism
      Aug 14: The agenda
      Aug 15: Good grazing!
      Aug 16: Voters of America, I need your help!
      Aug 19: The sniffer
      Aug 20: The tail wags the donkey
      Aug 21: Quiet: - quiet!!!
      Aug 22: Upsetting the apple cart!
      Aug 23: New hot line
      Aug 26: Happy days are here again!
      Aug 28: Don'cha understand? You're not supposed to win - your job is to gripe!
      Aug 29: What horse?!
      Aug 30: Just training for the finals!
      Sep 2: No caption
      Sep 3: Violence
      Sep 4: You're confused? - you don't know what confusion is!
      Sep 5: Lesson from Chicago
      Sep 6: Why do men climb mountains?
      Sep 9: Where one sits makes a difference!
      Sep 10: Great American debate!
      Sep 11: Watch your step, kid!
      Sep 13: But, dick, that's not a football!
      Sep 16: Gee whiz! - I didn't even know what I was doing!
      Sep 17: The hard core
      Sep 18: How do you stop a runaway juggernaut?
      Sep 19: Yeah! - we do need law and order!
      Sep 23: His campaign speech
      Sep 24: I'll steady it for you, Hubert!
      Sep 25: 10-9-8-7-6...
      Sep 26: The genie
      Sep 27: No caption
      Sep 30: That'll learn ya!
      Oct 1: That's what I call justice!
      Oct 2: Escalation!
      Oct 3: Brothers
      Oct 7: General, that's what I call courage!
      Oct 8: Hijacker
      Oct 9: Where's the dump?
      Oct 10: Witch's brew!
      Oct 11: The debate
      Oct 14: What's ailin' ya, anyhow? (Lyndon Johnson, Democrats, Vietnam)
      Oct 15: Who says I don't take a stand on issues?
      Oct 16: The ultimate in law and order!
      Oct 17: Super-demagogue
      Oct 18: Re-entry will be the problem
      Oct 21: Gentlemen, let's have one last violence binge and be done with it!
      Oct 22: Bird watcher
      Oct 23: Is man coming of age?
      Oct 24: Political scales
      Oct 25: Political dilemma
      Oct 28: Dick's secret campaign weapon
      Oct 29: The monkey on his back!
      Oct 30: 01;e man, one vote!
      Oct 31: We can take care of that later!
      Nov 1: She ought to be used to it by now!
      Nov 4: Well-l-l-not exactly a bomb-halt!
      Nov 5: His day
      Nov 6: Whose war is this, anyway?
      Nov 7: Dick's got the ball
      Nov 8: Greatest political force on earth
      Nov 11: Hey - you guys are rushing me!
      Nov 13: This way a little - steady now!
      Nov 14: But that's not what I mean by self-determination!
      Nov 15: Life is becoming so complicated
      Nov 18: What's that again, Mr. Hoover?
      Nov 19: Another cliff-hanger
      Nov 20: What a bird!
      Nov 21: 09, there'll be a debate, all right!
      Nov 22: Quick - the insecticide!
      Nov 25: There's nothing wrong with you that this won't cure!
      Nov 26: How about a little more kickback, Sam?
      Nov 27: What are the odds?
      Nov 28: Thankfulness is a point of view!
      Nov 29: Financial crisis - what's that?
      Dec 2: Ladies and gentlemen
      Dec 3: The rebound!
      Dec 4: If you think this easy try it yourself sometime
      Dec 5: Some people have no feeling for our fine old traditions!
      Dec 6: Boy! - what an assignment!
      Dec 9: Beginning of ideological warfare
      Dec 10: Rite flower country
      Dec 11: A round table for the Paris peace talks is quite appropriate!
      Dec 12: Sounds wonderful, but !
      Dec 13: Don't leave me now!
      Dec 16: No caption
      Dec 17: Traditional holiday toast
      Dec 18: For the man who has everything
      Dec 19: (no caption)
      Dec 27: Something has been added to the old globe
      Dec 30: Auld lang syne
    - 1969 Jan-Jun (Oversize 46)
      Jan 1: Mutiny aboard the space ship!
      Jan 2: Read all about it!
      Jan 3: Trying to sleep it off
      Jan 6: You still hanging around?
      Jan 7: There's gotta be money someplace!
      Jan 8: Still another agonizing reappraisal
      Jan 9: The hot pursuit